♪The evening breeze swirls in the moonlight♪
♪ نسيم المساء يحوم في ضوء القمر ♪
♪Falls on the corners of your mouth♪
♪ يقع على زوايا فمك ♪
♪With a shy smile on your face♪
♪ مع ابتسامة خجولة على وجهك ♪
♪Who should speak first♪
♪ من يجب أن يتكلم أولاً ♪
♪Maybe I can be a bit noisy♪
♪ ربما أستطيع أن أكون صاخبة قليلاً ♪
♪Don't want the atmosphere to get boring♪
♪ لا تريد أن يصبح الجو مملاً ♪
♪Love is quite wonderful♪
♪ الحب رائع جداً ♪
♪I like you but don't dare to tell you♪
♪ أنا معجب بك ولكن لا أجرؤ على إخبارك ♪
♪Oh, you are the shooting star breaking into the night sky♪
♪ أوه، أنت الشهاب الذي يقتحم سماء الليل ♪
♪Listen to the sound of the heart♪
♪ استمع إلى صوت القلب ♪
♪Encounter you at the right time♪
♪ نلتقي بك في الوقت المناسب ♪
♪Accompanied by courage♪
♪ مصحوبة بالشجاعة ♪
♪Oh, love needs no explanation♪
♪ أوه، الحب لا يحتاج إلى تفسير ♪
♪You are the meaning I strive for♪
♪أنت المعنى الذي أسعى من أجله♪
♪About your tomorrow and mood♪
♪ عن غدك وحالتك المزاجية ♪
♪Will slowly be occupied by me♪
♪ سوف أحتلها ببطء ♪
♪Oh love, blame you for not understanding♪
♪ يا حب ألومك على عدم الفهم ♪
♪I just want to come with true love for you♪
♪ أريد فقط أن آتي بالحب الحقيقي لك ♪
♪Enough anticipation♪
♪ كفى ترقباً ♪
♪Starlight falls into the arms♪
♪ يقع ضوء النجوم في الذراعين ♪
=Treasures Around=
= كنوز حولها =
=Episode 20=
=الحلقة 20=
(Peace and Tranquility)
(السلام والهدوء)
I have a request.
لدي طلب.
I've been in the house
لقد كنت في المنزل
serving the madam for over ten years.
خدمة السيدة لأكثر من عشر سنوات.
The madam rises at 5 am
السيدة تستيقظ في الساعة 5 صباحا
and sleeps at 9 pm.
وينام الساعة 9 مساءً.
Though she's old,
رغم أنها كبيرة في السن،
she loves sweets.
تحب الحلويات.
The madam's habits and likes
عادات السيدة وأمثالها
are imprinted in my bones.
مطبوع في عظامي.
Now that the madam has passed,
والآن بعد أن مرت السيدة،
I...
أنا...
Aside from sorrow,
وبعيداً عن الحزن
I find no purpose in staying here.
لا أجد أي غرض في البقاء هنا.
Today,
اليوم،
I request your permission
أطلب إذنك
to return home
للعودة إلى المنزل
to be a vegetarian and pray
أن تكون نباتيًا وتصلي
for the madam's peaceful next life,
من أجل حياة السيدة الهادئة القادمة،
free from suffering.
خالية من المعاناة.
Ms. Li,
السيدة لي،
since you've decided,
منذ أن قررت،
we won't keep you.
لن نحتفظ بك.
Thank you, Young Master.
شكرا لك، يونغ ماستر.
Thank you, Ms. Dandan.
شكرا لك، السيدة دندن.
Ms. Li,
السيدة لي،
I'll help you pack your things.
سأساعدك في حزم أغراضك.
Thank you, Ms. Shuangshuang.
شكرا لك، السيدة شوانغشوانغ.
The madam passed suddenly.
لقد مرت السيدة فجأة.
You must be very sad.
يجب أن تكون حزينا جدا.
Yes.
نعم.
With the madam gone,
مع رحيل السيدة،
I feel lost
أشعر بالضياع
as if nothing I do has any meaning.
كما لو أن لا شيء أفعله له أي معنى.
Do we know what illness took the madam?
هل نعرف ما هو المرض الذي أصاب السيدة؟
It was tuberculosis,
لقد كان مرض السل،
an old ailment.
مرض قديم.
It's the aconite herb.
إنها عشبة البيش.
If carefully prepared,
إذا تم إعدادها بعناية،
it can kill people
يمكن أن يقتل الناس
within half a day.
في غضون نصف يوم.
Thank you for taking care of the madam.
شكرا لك على رعاية السيدة.
I hope you live peacefully
أتمنى أن تعيش بسلام
after leaving here.
بعد مغادرته هنا.
Thank you, Ms. Shuangshuang.
شكرا لك، السيدة شوانغشوانغ.
Oh, no. Ms. Li has fainted!
أوه لا.  لقد أغمي على السيدة لي!
Dandan.
ضروري.
What's happening?
ماذا يحدث؟
She was fine just now.
لقد كانت بخير الآن.
I was just helping her pack.
لقد كنت فقط أساعدها في حزم أمتعتها.
She was ready to leave
وكانت مستعدة للمغادرة
but suddenly collapsed.
لكنه انهار فجأة.
Liu, go get a doctor!
ليو، اذهب واحصل على طبيب!
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Check her belongings
تحقق من متعلقاتها
for any emergency medicine.
لأي طب الطوارئ.
This...
هذا...
This is the aconite herb.
هذه هي عشبة البيش.
It contains aconitine,
أنه يحتوي على الأكونيتين
which can numb the nerves.
والتي يمكن أن تخدر الأعصاب.
It can cause rapid heartbeat,
يمكن أن يسبب سرعة ضربات القلب،
a drop in body temperature, and even death.
انخفاض في درجة حرارة الجسم، وحتى الموت.
Why would Ms. Li carry such a thing?
لماذا تحمل السيدة لي مثل هذا الشيء؟
Do you remember
هل تذكر
the bowl of soup by the madam's bed?
وعاء الحساء بجانب سرير السيدة؟
Ms. Li made that soup herself.
لقد صنعت السيدة لي هذا الحساء بنفسها.
Are you saying
هل تقول
Ms. Li killed the madam?
السيدة لي قتلت السيدة؟
Impossible.
مستحيل.
Ms. Li served the madam for years,
السيدة لي خدمت السيدة لسنوات،
always loyal.
دائما مخلصا.
The doctor said
وقال الطبيب
it was an old ailment.
لقد كان مرضًا قديمًا.
Spare me!
اعفنى!
Spare me, please!
إعذرني، من فضلك!
It was her!
لقد كانت هي!
She poisoned the madam!
لقد سممت السيدة!
This wicked woman!
هذه المرأة الشريرة!
She forced me to do it.
لقد أجبرتني على القيام بذلك.
If I didn't obey,
وإذا لم أطيع
she'd have me killed.
كانت ستقتلني.
I had no choice!
لم يكن لدي اي خيار!
But as a doctor,
ولكن كطبيب،
I failed to save lives
لقد فشلت في إنقاذ الأرواح
and instead caused death.
وبدلا من ذلك تسبب في الوفاة.
I can't live without the guilt.
لا أستطيع العيش بدون الشعور بالذنب.
The madam had no severe illness.
ولم تكن السيدة تعاني من مرض خطير.
She died
لقد ماتت
because of the colorless, tasteless
بسبب عديم اللون، لا طعم له
aconite herb in her soup.
عشب البيش في حساءها.
You...
أنت...
Why?
لماذا؟
How could you?
كيف استطعت؟
She treated you so well.
لقد عاملتك بشكل جيد.
Why did you harm her?
لماذا أذيتها؟
Treated me well?
هل تعاملني بشكل جيد؟
I served her carefully
لقد خدمتها بعناية
day and night for decades.
ليلا ونهارا لعقود من الزمن.
And what was I to her?
وماذا كنت لها؟
Just a dog.
مجرد كلب.
Why would I want to kill her?
لماذا أريد أن أقتلها؟
I've wanted her dead for years.
لقد أردتها ميتة لسنوات.
Shut up.
اسكت.
Liu,
ليو،
report this to the authorities.
الإبلاغ عن هذا إلى السلطات.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Go.
يذهب.
I was with the madam that day.
لقد كنت مع السيدة في ذلك اليوم.
Ms. Li made the lotus root soup
أعدت السيدة لي حساء جذر اللوتس
for the young master
للسيد الشاب
and Ms. Dandan.
والسيدة دندن.
The madam said Ophiopogon is cold by nature,
قالت السيدة إن أوفيوبوجون بارد بطبيعته،
not suitable for you,
غير مناسب لك،
so she took it herself.
فأخذتها بنفسها.
So that day,
لذلك في ذلك اليوم،
you meant to harm me and the young master.
لقد قصدت إيذائي والسيد الشاب.
We have no grudge.
ليس لدينا ضغينة.
Why would you harm me?
لماذا تؤذيني؟
Who put you up to this?
من الذي دفعك إلى هذا؟
Speak!
يتكلم!
That's right.
صحيح.
I wanted you dead.
أردتك ميتا.
I wanted all of you dead.
أردتكم جميعا ميتين.
Do I need someone to put me up to this?
هل أحتاج إلى شخص ما ليضعني في هذا؟
I was jealous and angry.
كنت غيورًا وغاضبًا.
I hated seeing you all happy,
لقد كرهت رؤيتكم جميعاً سعداء،
ignoring the servants.
إهمال الخدم
I wanted
أنا أردت
you privileged people
أيها الناس المتميزون
to taste pain too.
لتذوق الألم أيضاً.
(Wang Jiu,)
(وانغ جيو)
(I can't wait for you any longer.)
(لا أستطيع الانتظار بالنسبة لك بعد الآن.)
(In the next life,)
(في الحياة الآخرة)
(you must marry me.)
(يجب أن تتزوجيني.)
(Fine Gold and Good Jade)
(الذهب الخالص واليشم الجيد)
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Ms. Li is dead.
السيدة لي ماتت.
I'm sure.
أنا متأكد.
Shopkeeper.
صاحب متجر.
I'll check again.
سوف أتحقق مرة أخرى.
Get out.
اخرج.
As long as you stand up again,
طالما أنك تقف مرة أخرى،
Qipei Pavilion will prosper sooner or later.
سوف يزدهر جناح Qipei عاجلاً أم آجلاً.
I have confidence in you.
لدي ثقة فيكم.
Pei.
باي.
Mother.
الأم.
You're back.
لقد عدت.
Pei.
باي.
You can't go anywhere until you eat properly.
لا يمكنك الذهاب إلى أي مكان حتى تأكل بشكل صحيح.
Pei!
باي!
You brat.
أنت شقي.
Finish your meal before you go.
أنهي وجبتك قبل أن تذهب.
Pei, do you want to carve jade?
بي، هل تريد نحت اليشم؟
Shh.
صه.
Quiet.
هادئ.
What?
ماذا؟
I'm fishing.
أنا أصطاد.
I asked if you wanted to carve jade.
سألت إذا كنت تريد نحت اليشم.
I'm fishing!
أنا أصطاد!
Carve jade.
نحت اليشم.
You brat. Fine.
أنت شقي.  بخير.
Just wait.
فقط انتظر.
- What are you doing? - Are you still fishing?
- ماذا تفعل؟  - هل مازلت تصطاد؟
- You...
- ماذا تفعل؟  - أنت...
Are you pointing at me? What are you doing?
هل تشير إلي؟  ماذا تفعل؟
Put it down.
ضعه أرضا، أنزله.
- I won't. - Put it down.
- أنا لن.  - ضعه أرضا، أنزله.
I won't.
أنا لن.
You brat, come here!
أيها الشقي، تعال هنا!
No.
لا.
Why are you going to Flower Pavilion?
لماذا أنت ذاهب إلى جناح الزهور؟
To squander your fortune, of course.
لتبديد ثروتك، بطبيعة الحال.
What else?
ماذا بعد؟
You unfilial son.
أيها الابن غير المخلص.
You're driving me mad.
أنت تقودني إلى الجنون.
Look at you, all grown up,
أنظر إليك، لقد كبرت جميعًا،
still so irresponsible.
لا يزال غير مسؤول.
Stop right there!
توقف هناك!
Stop!
قف!
I...
أنا...
I don't have a mother anymore.
ليس لدي أم بعد الآن.
Why?
لماذا؟
Pei Pei,
باي باي,
The madam was the best mother in the world.
وكانت السيدة أفضل أم في العالم.
You've made her proud.
لقد جعلتها فخورة.
Here.
هنا.
For you,
لك،
I can be your spy in the Pei family.
يمكنني أن أكون جاسوسًا لك في عائلة باي.
To help you achieve your great plans,
لمساعدتك في تحقيق خططك العظيمة،
I'm willing to do anything.
أنا على استعداد لفعل أي شيء.
Guixiang.
جويكسيانج.
I'm sorry to put you through this.
أنا آسف لوضعك في هذا.
You never minded my background as a maid,
لم تهتم أبدًا بخلفيتي كخادمة،
and you were the first
وكنت الأول
to make me a promise in this world.
أن تجعل لي وعداً في هذه الدنيا.
What does a little hardship matter?
ما أهمية القليل من المشقة؟
Guixiang,
قويشيانغ،
I never imagined
لم أتخيل أبدا
you'd sacrifice your life
سوف تضحي بحياتك
to protect me.
لحمايتي.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
But don't worry.
لكن لا تقلق.
I will avenge you.
سوف أنتقم لك.
The Pei family.
عائلة باي.
I won't let them go.
لن أسمح لهم بالرحيل.
Who are you burning paper for?
لمن تحرق الورق؟
It's so late.
لقد فات الأوان.
Why are you still awake?
لماذا لا تزال مستيقظا؟
I'm asking you who you're doing this for.
أنا أسألك من أجل من تفعل هذا.
It can't be Madam Pei, can it?
لا يمكن أن تكون السيدة باي، أليس كذلك؟
Could it be...?
هل من الممكن ذلك...؟
Yes, it's her.
نعم، انها لها.
Where do you think I've been getting
أين تعتقد أنني قد وصلت
the latest news and designs from Qipei Pavilion
آخر الأخبار والتصميمات من Qipei Pavilion
all these years?
كل هذه السنوات؟
My plan was
كانت خطتي
to kill Pei Pei and Shan Dandan,
لقتل باي باي وشان داندان،
the two stumbling blocks.
العائقين.
But that old fox
ولكن هذا الثعلب القديم
died first.
مات أولا.
It's just
انه فقط
a pity for my Guixiang.
من المؤسف لبلدي Guixiang.
Are you mad?
هل انت مجنون؟
How could you kill someone?
كيف يمكنك قتل شخص ما؟
What else could I do?
ماذا يمكنني أن أفعل؟
Watch our hundred-year legacy be destroyed?
مشاهدة تراثنا مائة عام يتم تدميرها؟
So what?
وماذا في ذلك؟
Don't we have strength?
أليس لدينا القوة؟
Can't we start over?
ألا يمكننا أن نبدأ من جديد؟
But your hands are stained with blood,
ولكن أيديكم ملطخة بالدماء
involved in murder. Can you wash it clean?
متورط في القتل.  هل يمكنك غسلها نظيفة؟
Who do you think you killed?
من تعتقد أنك قتلت؟
Madam Pei!
سيدتي باي!
The madam of Qipei Pavilion.
سيدة جناح Qipei.
How can you speak so lightly?
كيف يمكنك التحدث بخفة؟
Fool.
أحمق.
Starting over?
البدء من جديد؟
You make it sound so easy.
أنت تجعله يبدو سهلا للغاية.
With what will we start over?
بماذا سنبدأ من جديد؟
Is there still time?
هل ما زال هناك وقت؟
Is there still a chance?
هل ما زالت هناك فرصة؟
Jue,
جوي,
fate has placed a great responsibility on us.
لقد وضع القدر مسؤولية كبيرة علينا.
It has come to this.
. لقد أتت إلى هذا
We have no way back now.
ليس لدينا طريق العودة الآن.
I don't want this either.
أنا لا أريد هذا أيضا.
But now,
لكن الآن،
Guixiang's life is lost.
ضاعت حياة Guixiang.
No matter what,
بغض النظر،
I'll fight them to the death.
سأقاتلهم حتى الموت.
Come with me.
تعال معي.
Why is there a secret room?
لماذا هناك غرفة سرية؟
Come in.
ادخل.
How could there be a dungeon?
كيف يمكن أن يكون هناك زنزانة؟
I never knew all these years.
لم أعرف قط كل هذه السنوات.
Who...
من...
Who is this?
من هذا؟
(Pei Chufeng, Qipei Pavilion)
(باي تشوفنغ، جناح تشيبي)
Don't hit me.
لا تضربني.
I'll paint.
سوف أرسم.
This...
هذا...
This is Pei Pei's biological father,
هذا هو والد باي باي البيولوجي،
Pei Chufeng.
باي تشوفنغ.
Pei Chufeng?
باي تشوفينج؟
This...
هذا...
What on earth is going on?
ماذا يحدث بحق السماء؟
At this point,
عند هذه النقطة،
I won't hide it from you anymore.
لن أخفي الأمر عنك بعد الآن.
When you were young,
عندما كنت يافعا،
Qipei Pavilion's quality and craftsmanship
الجودة والحرفية في Qipei Pavilion
always overshadowed us,
دائما ما يطغى علينا
making your father unable to lift his head,
جعل والدك غير قادر على رفع رأسه،
until the Emperor
حتى الامبراطور
(Guard Zhao, Qipei Pavilion) wanted the Moonlight Crown.
(الحارس تشاو، جناح تشيبي) أراد تاج ضوء القمر.
The City Lord appointed
عين سيد المدينة
this old guy as the chief designer.
هذا الرجل العجوز باعتباره المصمم الرئيسي.
Your father had no choice but to steal the treasure.
لم يكن أمام والدك خيار سوى سرقة الكنز.
There's an assassin!
هناك قاتل!
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Hand over the Crown.
تسليم التاج.
(Shan Jingtian, a warrior)
(شان جينغ تيان، محارب)
Wang Jiu!
وانغ جيو!
Shan Jingtian.
شان جينغتيان.
Give me the Crown.
أعطني التاج.
We agreed that day.
اتفقنا في ذلك اليوم.
I would get the Crown for you.
سأحصل على التاج من أجلك.
You get the Crown,
تحصل على التاج،
and I get the water amber on it
وأحصل على العنبر الماء عليه
for my wife's illness.
لمرض زوجتي .
What are you doing now?
ماذا تفعل الآن؟
Using water amber as medicine
استخدام عنبر الماء كدواء
to treat all diseases.
لعلاج جميع الأمراض.
You really believe that?
هل تصدق ذلك حقا؟
Such an ignorant fool.
مثل هذا الأحمق الجاهل.
You...
أنت...
I valued you and hired you to steal the Crown.
لقد قدرتك وقمت بتعيينك لسرقة التاج.
Now that I have the Crown,
الآن بعد أن حصلت على التاج،
you should go to the afterlife.
يجب أن تذهب إلى الآخرة.
Didn't you see this coming?
لم ترى هذا القادمة؟
Yes. Water amber is precious,
نعم.  العنبر المائي ثمين،
but there are countless treasures in the world.
ولكن هناك كنوز لا تعد ولا تحصى في العالم.
The real value is in the amazing craftsmanship
القيمة الحقيقية هي في الحرفية المذهلة
of the Crown.
من التاج.
You wouldn't understand.
لن تفهم.
Think about it as a ghost in the afterlife.
فكر في الأمر كشبح في الحياة الآخرة.
Sir,
سيد،
I was deceived
لقد خدعت
into stealing your precious treasure.
لسرقة كنزك الثمين
Today, I'll sacrifice my life
اليوم سأضحي بحياتي
to return it to its rightful owner.
لإعادته إلى صاحبه الشرعي.
At that time, Qipei Pavilion couldn't produce the Crown.
في ذلك الوقت، لم يتمكن جناح تشيبي من إنتاج التاج.
So, we seized
لذلك، قبضنا
the opportunity
الفرصه
and presented our prepared backup crown.
وقدمنا ​​التاج الاحتياطي المُجهز.
From then on, our reputation soared nationwide.
ومنذ ذلك الحين، ارتفعت سمعتنا على الصعيد الوطني.
So, Suyu Pavilion became what it is today.
لذا، أصبح Suyu Pavilion على ما هو عليه اليوم.
For so many years,
لسنوات عديدة،
I only knew there was a drawing of the Crown in our house.
كنت أعرف فقط أن هناك رسمًا للتاج في منزلنا.
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
(I'll kill you together.)
(سأقتلكما معًا.)
Careful! It's poison!
حذر!  إنه سم!
You go first.
تذهب أولا.
I entrust my daughter to you.
أعهد إليك بابنتي.
I need to get the remaining Crown.
أنا بحاجة للحصول على التاج المتبقي.
Take good care of her for me.
اعتني بها جيدًا من أجلي.
Actually, we've always had the Crown.
في الواقع، لقد كان لدينا التاج دائمًا.
But one half
ولكن نصف واحد
was taken by that thief.
تم أخذه من قبل ذلك اللص.
Now, even with our skills,
الآن، حتى مع مهاراتنا،
we can't master its craftsmanship.
لا يمكننا إتقان صنعتها.
Remember when your father
تذكر عندما والدك
taught you some techniques,
علمتك بعض التقنيات،
but you couldn't master them?
لكنك لا تستطيع السيطرة عليهم؟
Those were the techniques from the Crown.
تلك كانت التقنيات من التاج.
So,
لذا،
because I couldn't master them,
لأنني لم أتمكن من السيطرة عليهم،
you broke
لقد كسرت
Pei Pei's hand?
يد باي باي؟
Yes.
نعم.
After dealing with the old,
بعد التعامل مع القديم
the young one emerged to fight with you.
خرج الشاب ليقاتل معك.
How could your father let them succeed?
كيف سمح لهم والدك بالنجاح؟
(It's your fault for outshining Jue.)
(إنه خطأك لأنك تفوقت على جو.)
(Your talent is your fault.)
(موهبتك هي خطأك.)
So, all these years,
لذا، كل هذه السنوات،
I never truly won against him.
لم أنتصر عليه أبدًا حقًا.
I was just a clown,
لقد كنت مجرد مهرج،
feeling proud for years.
الشعور بالفخر لسنوات.
The one who laughs last is the true winner.
الشخص الذي يضحك أخيرًا هو الفائز الحقيقي.
Jue,
جوي,
don't blame me and your father for being ruthless.
لا تلومني ووالدك لكوننا قاسيين.
The world's contests are fatal.
مسابقات العالم قاتلة.
Only the victor can rule.
وحده المنتصر يستطيع أن يحكم.
Look at Pei Pei.
انظر إلى باي باي.
As soon as he gained the raw stone,
بمجرد أن حصل على الحجر الخام،
he was eager to destroy us.
كان حريصًا على تدميرنا.
When the Crown was lost,
عندما ضاع التاج
your father spread rumors,
والدك ينشر الشائعات
making people suspect he stole it himself.
مما يجعل الناس يشككون في أنه سرقها بنفسه.
The City Lord investigated him three times,
لقد حقق معه سيد المدينة ثلاث مرات،
making him live in constant fear,
مما يجعله يعيش في خوف دائم،
afraid to let his son shine.
خائف من السماح لابنه بالتألق.
But Pei Pei
لكن باي باي
glanced at the Crown's dissection diagram
ألقى نظرة خاطفة على مخطط تشريح التاج
and could mimic its techniques
ويمكن أن تحاكي تقنياتها
to seventy percent.
إلى سبعين بالمائة.
For you, for the Su family,
من أجلك ومن أجل عائلة سو،
your father and I had no choice.
والدك وأنا لم يكن لدينا خيار.
So, a few years after the Crown was lost,
لذلك، بعد سنوات قليلة من فقدان التاج،
there were rumors that Pei Chufeng
كانت هناك شائعات بأن باي تشوفنغ
died in a fire
مات في حريق
while on a business trip.
أثناء رحلة عمل.
That was you too?
هل كنت أنت أيضاً؟
Yes.
نعم.
Your father and I brought him here.
أنا ووالدك أحضرناه إلى هنا.
It was you.
لقد كنت أنت.
You're lucky
انت محظوظ
to survive this.
للبقاء على قيد الحياة هذا.
Since you're still alive,
وبما أنك لا تزال على قيد الحياة،
you'll be used by us.
سيتم استخدامك من قبلنا.
One, to stop him from investigating the theft.
الأول، لمنعه من التحقيق في السرقة.
Two, to prevent him from teaching his son.
الثاني: أن يمنعه من تعليم ابنه.
Three, to use his skills
ثالثا، لاستخدام مهاراته
to pave the way for the Su family.
لتمهيد الطريق لعائلة سو.
Right now,
الآن،
he still has a crucial use.
لا يزال لديه استخدام حاسم.
What do you plan to do?
ماالذي تخطط أن تفعله؟
Use his hands
استخدم يديه
to completely destroy Qipei Pavilion.
لتدمير جناح Qipei بالكامل.
((Peace and Tranquility)
((السلام والهدوء)
(Qipei Pavilion)
(جناح كيبي)
Ms. Shan.
السيدة شان.
(Qipei Pavilion Promotion Plan) This is our shop's promotion plan.
(خطة ترويج جناح Qipei) هذه هي خطة الترويج لمتجرنا.
Please have a look.
ألق نظرة من فضلك.
The plan is thorough and comprehensive.
الخطة شاملة وشاملة.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
please proceed accordingly.
يرجى المضي قدما وفقا لذلك.
As long as you're satisfied.
طالما كنت راضيا.
I'll have someone arrange it right away.
سأطلب من شخص ما ترتيب الأمر على الفور.
But...
لكن...
Do you have any other thoughts?
هل لديك أي أفكار أخرى؟
Our main shop is well-known.
متجرنا الرئيسي معروف.
Besides other shops' promotions,
بالإضافة إلى العروض الترويجية للمحلات الأخرى،
we can bring old customers to new shops.
يمكننا جلب العملاء القدامى إلى المتاجر الجديدة.
For anyone buying jewelry at our main shop,
لكل من يشتري مجوهرات من متجرنا الرئيسي،
we'll ask them to pick up goods at other shops.
سنطلب منهم استلام البضائع من المتاجر الأخرى.
As an apology,
على سبيل الاعتذار،
we'll prepare small gifts at other shops.
سنقوم بإعداد هدايا صغيرة في متاجر أخرى.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
I'll tell the young master.
سأخبر السيد الشاب.
We'll do it as you say.
سنفعل ذلك كما تقول.
- Pei... - Young Master.
- بى... - السيد الشاب.
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
Young Master, Ms. Shan.
السيد الشاب، السيدة شان.
I'll arrange it now.
سوف أقوم بترتيب الأمر الآن.
Coming.
آت.
(Ancient Jade Dealer)
(تاجر اليشم القديم)
You're right.
أنت على حق.
As the only head of the Pei family,
بصفته الرئيس الوحيد لعائلة باي،
I can't fall.
لا أستطيع السقوط.
Smile.
يبتسم.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
(The melting technique of South Bead and gold on the Crown.)
(تقنية ذوبان الخرزة الجنوبية والذهب على التاج.)
Shuangshuang,
شوانغشوانغ،
I was framed.
لقد كنت مؤطر.
I failed your mother,
لقد خذلت والدتك
and I failed you.
ولقد خذلتك.
Shuangshuang,
شوانغشوانغ،
you didn't go to the workshop?
لم تذهب إلى ورشة العمل؟
No.
لا.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
I want to talk to Mr. Pei alone.
أريد أن أتحدث إلى السيد باي وحده.
Is that alright?
هل هذا جيد؟
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
You two talk. I'll make some pastries.
أنتما تتحدثان.  سأقوم بإعداد بعض المعجنات.
What do you want to discuss?
ماذا تريد مناقشته؟
You made this?
لقد جعلتم هذا؟
Yes.
نعم.
A small gift for Dandan.
هدية صغيرة لداندان.
For the lost techniques of the Moonlight Crown,
بالنسبة للتقنيات المفقودة لتاج ضوء القمر،
whether it's gold and silver inlay, filigree carving,
سواء كان ذلك ترصيعًا بالذهب والفضة، أو نحتًا مخرمًا،
or hollow vertical carving,
أو نحت عمودي مجوف،
you've mastered them all.
لقد أتقنتهم جميعًا.
Who taught you?
من علمك؟
My father participated in the design of the Crown.
شارك والدي في تصميم التاج.
He was familiar with many techniques.
كان على دراية بالعديد من التقنيات.
When I was young,
عندما كنت صغيرا،
I was lucky to see the actual Crown.
لقد كنت محظوظاً لرؤية التاج الفعلي.
Plus, my father taught me,
بالإضافة إلى ذلك، علمني والدي،
so I know a bit.
لذلك أعرف قليلا.
Other techniques
تقنيات أخرى
occasionally appear in the world.
تظهر في بعض الأحيان في العالم.
What about the melting technique of South Bead and gold?
ماذا عن تقنية صهر حبة الجنوب والذهب؟
Except for the Sun family's technique on the Crown,
باستثناء تقنية عائلة الشمس على التاج،
nowhere else has it.
لا يوجد مكان آخر لديه.
You only saw it a few times as a child,
لم ترها إلا مرات قليلة عندما كنت طفلاً،
yet mastered it.
ومع ذلك أتقنها.
You must have studied the actual Crown
يجب أن تكون قد درست التاج الفعلي
for over ten years
لأكثر من عشر سنوات
to achieve this.
لتحقيق هذا.
What?
ماذا؟
How could I have the actual Crown?
كيف يمكنني الحصول على التاج الفعلي؟
I was just influenced by my father.
لقد تأثرت فقط بوالدي.
Influenced?
تأثر؟
You said you learned from your father.
قلت أنك تعلمت من والدك.
Who did he learn from?
ومن الذي تعلم منه؟
The Crown was crafted
تم صنع التاج
by dozens of master artisans.
من قبل العشرات من الحرفيين الرئيسيين.
Your father was the chief designer,
والدك كان كبير المصممين،
but not uniquely skilled.
ولكن ليس ماهرًا بشكل فريد.
As a kid,
كطفل،
you mastered so many core techniques.
لقد أتقنت العديد من التقنيات الأساسية.
Do you find that reasonable?
هل تجد ذلك معقولا؟
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
Are you accusing my father
هل تتهم والدي؟
of stealing everyone's work?
لسرقة عمل الجميع؟
After the Moonlight Crown was lost,
بعد فقدان تاج ضوء القمر،
your father forbade you from using its techniques.
لقد منعك والدك من استخدام تقنياته.
Do you remember?
هل تذكر؟
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
Something terrible happened.
حدث شيء فظيع.
Young Master. Bad news.
المعلم الصغير.  اخبار سيئة.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Something's wrong.
هناك خطأ.
(Qipei Pavilion)
(جناح كيبي)
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
The City Lord's order is here.
أمر سيد المدينة هنا.
(City Lord's Order) Pei Chufeng, former head of Qipei Pavilion,
(أمر سيد المدينة) باي تشوفنغ، الرئيس السابق لجناح تشيبي،
stole the Moonlight Crown.
سرق تاج ضوء القمر.
Now it's been confirmed.
الآن تم تأكيد ذلك.
Qipei Pavilion is to be sealed.
سيتم إغلاق جناح Qipei.
What?
ماذا؟
Where's the evidence?
أين الدليل؟
How dare you slander my father!
كيف تجرؤ على التشهير بأبي!
Slander?
القذف؟
"I, Pei Chufeng, lost my mind"
"أنا، باي تشوفنغ، فقدت عقلي"
"and collaborated with the thief Shan Jingtian"
"وتعاون مع اللص شان جينغ تيان"
"to steal the Moonlight Crown."
"لسرقة تاج ضوء القمر."
"After getting the treasure, I lived in fear"
"بعد حصولي على الكنز، عشت في خوف"
"and couldn't live peacefully."
"ولا يمكن أن يعيشوا بسلام."
"Aware of my heavy sins,"
"أعلم بذنوبي العظيمة"
"today, I willingly surrender"
"اليوم، أنا أستسلم عن طيب خاطر"
"and burn myself in another city to atone."
"وأحرق نفسي في مدينة أخرى للتكفير".
"I voluntarily return all family assets to the public."
"أعيد طوعًا جميع أصول العائلة إلى الجمهور."
Recently, the City Lord's confidants received
في الآونة الأخيرة، استقبل المقربون من سيد المدينة
parts of the stolen Crown and a letter.
أجزاء من التاج المسروق ورسالة.
Do the handwriting and fingerprints look familiar?
هل تبدو الكتابة اليدوية وبصمات الأصابع مألوفة؟
Hurry. Hurry.
عجل.  عجل.
Move.
يتحرك.
Copy it.
انسخه.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'll clear us.
سوف أبرئنا.
"I, Pei Chufeng, lost my mind"
"أنا، باي تشوفنغ، فقدت عقلي"
"and collaborated with the thief..."
"وتعاونوا مع اللص..."
Don't blame me for being ruthless.
لا تلومني لكوني عديم الرحمة.
You forced me.
لقد أجبرتني.
Dandan! Dandan!
ضروري!  ضروري!
Ms. Shan fainted!
أغمي على السيدة شان!
(Peace and Tranquility)
(السلام والهدوء)
♪Maybe the leaves falling from the tree♪
♪ ربما الأوراق تتساقط من الشجرة ♪
♪Maybe the lights reflect on the water♪
♪ ربما تنعكس الأضواء على الماء ♪
♪The butterflies in your eyes♪
♪الفراشات في عينيك ♪
♪Also dancing joyfully in my heart♪
♪ كما أرقص بفرح في قلبي ♪
♪Maybe it's the wind kissing your cheek♪
♪ ربما تكون الريح هي التي تقبل خدك ♪
♪Maybe I feel your specialness♪
♪ ربما أشعر بتميزك ♪
♪Stuck by your side♪
♪ عالق بجانبك ♪
♪Feels like owning the whole world♪
♪يشعر وكأنك تمتلك العالم كله♪
♪Like a reflection, distant yet close and overlapping♪
♪ مثل انعكاس، بعيد ولكنه قريب ومتداخل ♪
♪ Accompanying you day by day, year by year ♪
♪ يرافقك يوما بعد يوم، سنة بعد سنة ♪
♪Occasionally the thoughts of you♪
♪أحيانًا أفكارك♪
♪Ripples on the surface♪
♪ تموجات على السطح ♪
♪You can hear my unspoken thoughts♪
♪ يمكنك سماع أفكاري غير المعلنة ♪
♪Like a reflection, distant yet close and overlapping♪
♪ مثل انعكاس، بعيد ولكنه قريب ومتداخل ♪
♪ Accompanying you day by day, year by year ♪
♪ يرافقك يوما بعد يوم، سنة بعد سنة ♪
♪The plot of that story♪
♪ حبكة تلك القصة ♪
♪Contending in beauty with you♪
♪أتنافس معك في الجمال♪
♪Quarreling and noisy♪
♪ تشاجر وصاخبة ♪
♪The blooming flowers become a celebration♪
♪ الزهور المتفتحة تصبح احتفالاً ♪
♪Maybe it's the wind kissing your cheek♪
♪ ربما تكون الريح هي التي تقبل خدك ♪
♪Maybe I feel your specialness♪
♪ ربما أشعر بتميزك ♪
♪Stuck by your side♪
♪ عالق بجانبك ♪
♪Feels like owning the whole world♪
♪يشعر وكأنك تمتلك العالم كله♪
♪Like a reflection, distant yet close and overlapping♪
♪ مثل انعكاس، بعيد ولكنه قريب ومتداخل ♪
♪ Accompanying you day by day, year by year ♪
♪ يرافقك يوما بعد يوم، سنة بعد سنة ♪
♪Occasionally the thoughts of you♪
♪أحيانًا أفكارك♪
♪Ripples on the surface♪
♪ تموجات على السطح ♪
♪You can hear my unspoken thoughts♪
♪ يمكنك سماع أفكاري غير المعلنة ♪
♪Like a reflection, distant yet close and overlapping♪
♪ مثل انعكاس، بعيد ولكنه قريب ومتداخل ♪
♪ Accompanying you day by day, year by year ♪
♪ يرافقك يوما بعد يوم، سنة بعد سنة ♪
♪The plot of that story♪
♪ حبكة تلك القصة ♪
♪Contending in beauty with you♪
♪أتنافس معك في الجمال♪
♪Quarreling and noisy♪
♪ تشاجر وصاخبة ♪
♪The blooming flowers become a celebration♪
♪ الزهور المتفتحة تصبح احتفالاً ♪